자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
이런 술이 50달러나 해?
장난해, 아저씨?
50 bucks for some crunk juice?
You got to be kidding me, man.
40달러도 안되겠는걸?
They ain't got no 40s?
도와드릴까요?
Can I help you?
현금 몽땅 내놔!
Give me the cash!
- 이리와, 자식아!
- 어서, 빨리!
Move, punk! / Move, hurry up!
- 지금 당장!
- 내놔!
Let's go! Now! / Come on!
왜 그래!
You crazy, man!
- 미쳤어!
- 응, 엘!
- Loco!
- Yo, el!
이 사람 맡아
Cover this fool.
알았어
Got you.
꼼짝하지 마
Don't move.
네가 마무리해
Finish it, man.
- 다 가져가도 좋으니...
- 조용히 해!
- You took everything...
- Shut up!
헥터, 쏴버려
Hector, blast that fool.
뒤쪽에 가서 가게
주인이랑 얘기해 봐
Go back and talk to the bodega owner.
하나라도 건질 게 있는지
잘 살펴. 얘기 잘 하라고
See if you can find anything out.
Be nice to him.
- 안녕하세요, 형사님들
- 수고하네, 경사
- Evening, detectives.
- Sergeant.
포도주 자국과 핏자국을
구분하기 힘드네요
Can't tell where the blood ends
and the wine begins.
어렵지 않게 할 수 있는데
Actually, you can.
점성과 색이 서로 다르거든요
Viscosity and color are different.
역시 과학자들은...
Scientists.
구조대원들이 오기 전에
숨졌습니다
lost him before
paramedics arrived.
- 뒤에 목격자 둘이 있어요
- 진술은 했나?
- Two in the back.
- Did he make a statement?
히스패닉 계 남자 셋인데
Three unknown male hispanics,
10대 후반에 둘은 무장했어요
late teens, two armed.
불량배들이군요
Gangbangers.
지역 원주민들은 고급주택화
하는 것을 위협으로 여기지
Most of the old-time residents
see gentrification as a threat.
그 불량배들이
희생양을 선택한 거지
The gangs,
they see fresh meat.
스텔라 / 예?
Stella. / Yeah?
발자국이 뛰어가는 모양인데
Footprints spaced in a run.
깨진 포도주 위로 말이야
피해자는 도망가려 했군
Right through the wine.
Vic was running for his life.
인간이 얼마나 냉혈한이
될 수 있는지 보여주네요
About as cold-blooded as it gets.
다른 건 없나, 경사?
Anything else, sergeant?
길 건너 서점 점원 말이
세 명이 뛰어서 도망갔답니다
Bookstore clerk across the
street said the three fled on foot.
- 다른 목격자는?
- 포도주 가게 주인하고
- Any other witnesses?
- Bodega owner,
다른 점원이 있는데
둘 다 할 말이 없다네요
check cashing clerk
both have nothing to say.
사람들이 갱들에 대한 증언은
해봤자 손해라는 걸 아니까요
The locals know better than to go
on record against the gangs.
아무리 그래도 갱들이...
Unfortunately for gangs...
증거까지 위협할 순 없지
they can't intimidate evidence.
자막편집/싱크
송미혜(smh8119@nate.com)
한글번역
임한결(hankyoul@nate.com)
게리 시니즈(맥 테일러 役)
CSI 레벨3(반장), 전문분야 : 전문자료수집/분석
멜리나 카나카레데스(스텔라 보나세라 役)
CSI 레벨2, 전문분야 : 총기류
카마인 지오비나죠(대니 메셔 役)
CSI 레벨1, 전문분야 : 사건의 재구성
바네사 페를리토(에이든 번 役)
CSI 레벨1, 전문분야 : 복안(復顔)기법
힐 하퍼(쉘던 호크스 役)
검시관, 전문분야 : Forensic Medicine(법의학)
에디 카힐(던 플랙 役)
뉴욕시 경찰청 형사
CSI: NY
1x17 The Fall
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON CBS: 2005/03/02
9mm예요
Nine millimeter.
두 배로 고생 좀 하겠어요
Did you remember
to double-glove?
이 피와 유리조각들 때문에
난 세 배로 고생인걸
All this blood and glass,
I triple-gloved.
좋은 쪽으로 생각하세요
적어도 이 안은 따뜻하잖아요
Looking at the bright side,
at least it's warm in here.
그래, 하지만 추위 때문에
Yeah, but the cold still kills us.
놈들이 두꺼운 옷을 입었고
지문이나 머리카락, DNA를
All the heavy clothing lessens
the chance the three left
많이 남기지 않았어
behind prints, hair, DNA.
정말 도움이 안 되네요
Mac, you're not helping.
유리조각은 우릴
도와줄지도 몰라
The glass may have
worked in our favor.
싹 쓸어서 가지고 갈 거니까
I'm swabbing every sample.
피해자 말고 다른 사람의
혈흔을 찾을지도 모르지
Maybe there's a second bleeder.
하긴 총을 쏜 범인이 모르고
남기고 간 경우도 없진 않죠
Wouldn't be the first time
showing off got a shooter nailed.
이것 좀 보세요
Got something.
일회용 라이터인데
여기서 파는 게 아니에요
Disposable lighter.
They don't sell these here.
주머니에서 뭔가를 급하게
The kind of thing
that falls from a pocket
뺄 때 떨어트리기도 하지
when you're removing
something else in haste.
만약 장갑을 끼고 있다면
Yeah, and if you
were wearing gloves,
라이터 켜기가 좀 어려웠겠죠
it would be pretty difficult to use it.
빙고
Bingo.
더블 빙고
Double bingo.
- 감시카메라네요
- 고급 기종이야
- Surveillance camera.
- High end.
아마 뒤쪽에 있는 컴퓨터로
전송되고 있을 걸
Probably transmits
to a computer in the back.
손전등이 다른 무엇보다
자주 쓰이는 거니까
You use your flashlight more
than anything on your belt.
항상 추가 배터리를
가지고 다녀야해
Always bring extra batteries.
말씀하신 거 기억 잘 해요
Remember all the lessons, rookie.
불쑥 자주 물어볼 겁니다
This guy likes pop quizzes.
됐네, 괜히 신참 기죽이지 마
All right, now, don't
break his aggies.
그래요. 제 기를 4년 동안
잘 살려 주신 것처럼 말이죠
Oh, yeah, like you didn't
break mine for four years.
잘 지내셨죠
Come here. Good to see you.
내 밑에서 수습 받은
도날드 플랙 주니어
My former charge,
Donald Flack Jr.,
전설적인 뉴욕 경찰의 아드님이지
Son of the NYPD legend.
- 아버님은 어떠셔?
- 여전하시죠
- Hey, how's your old man?
- Eh, you know, the same.
플랙 / 안녕하세요
Hey, Flack. / Hey.
동네 불량배들이 용의자라면서요
Hear we're looking for bangers.
세 명. 두 명이 9mm권총 소지했고
안 쪽은 거의 전쟁터야
Three. Two had nine-mils.
It's nagasaki in there;
나하고 이 주변 좀 돌아보자
I'm gonna need your help
on the perimeter.
네. 뛰어서 도망갔다면
우선 무기를 빨리 버렸을 겁니다
All right, fled on foot,
probably ditched their weapons quickly.
경과 계속 알려줘, 플랙
Keep me posted, Flack.
- 서쪽으로 갔다고 했어 / 갑시다
- 여기 지키고 있어
- Ran west. / Let's go.
- Hey, sit tight.
갱들 잡으러 가 볼까
Make old folks.
좋아, 자네가 그 애들이라면
Okay, you're a kid,
살인을 저지른 후
you murdered,
도망가고 있다
you're running.
전과까지 있다면
Got priors,
방금 쓴 무기를
갖고 있을 수 없죠
can't keep a hot weapon.
길에 내던지고 갔을 거야
Unwise to chuck it in the street.
골목이 너무 많은데
Plenty of alleys.
저쪽 모퉁이로 가지
Couple around the corner.
여긴 너무 깨끗해
창문도 너무 많고
Too clean.
Too many windows.
여기야. 첫 번째 놈이
먼저 던졌을 거야
Here.
Alpha maggot would throw first.
그런 놈들 패턴은
익히 알지, 도니
We know their pattern, Donnie.
가보죠!
Let's move.
여기 찾았어!
Here we go!
두 번째 놈이 첫 번째 놈이 하는 걸
보고 다음 골목에서 똑같이 했어요
Beta maggot sees alpha throw,
does likewise in the next alley.
실력이 여전한 걸
보니 든든하군, 도니
I'm glad a few things stuck, Donnie.
안녕하세요
CSI 대니 메셔 요원입니다
How you doing?
Danny Messer, crime lab.
시체는 어디 있습니까?
You know where the body's at?
세상에
Wow.
이 덩치로 왜 차양을
못 뚫었을까....
Guy this big couldn't just
fall through the awning?
캐노피예요 / 뭐라고?
It's a canopy. / What?
차양은 창문에 덮는 거고
벽에 붙이는 건 캐노피라고 해요
Awnings cover windows,
canopies run out to the curb.
삼촌이 퀸즈에서 그걸
만드시거든요
My uncle manufactures
them in Queens.
어쨌든, 이것 때문에
엉덩이가 아프다고
Either way, it's a pain
in my gluteus maximus.
어떤 거 같아요?
tell me about it.
죽은 지 얼마나 됐어요?
Any idea how long
he's been dead?
시반이 한 쪽에 앉았고
Lividity set in on one side.
사후경직도 어느 정도 있으니
Some rigor.
이 자세로 적어도 4시간은
여기 있었을 거야
Had to have been in this
position at least four hours.
그럼 시반이 생기기 한참 전에
떨어졌겠네요
So he fell long before
he was spotted.
4층 건물인데 어느 층에서
떨어진 건지 궁금하네요
Four stories.
Ah, I wonder which one.
3층에서 파티를 했다고 들었어
I'm hearing a party
on the third floor.
그리고 오른쪽 어깨에
기름얼룩이 있더라고
And I noticed an oily smudge
on his right shoulder.
알았어요
I got it.
와, 이 사람 멜빈 헤크만이네요
Wow, this is Melvin Heckman.
멜빈 헤크만이 누군데?
Who's Melvin Heckman?
그러니까, 뉴욕에서
활동하는 거물급 프로듀서죠
He is, like, New York's
biggest producer.
이 사람 할아버지가 영화 스튜디오도
가지고 있고, 영화계 귀족이랄까...
His grandfather owns a movie studio.
They're, like... film royalty.
이제 더 이상 레드카펫으로
대접받을 일은 없겠네
Well, no more red carpet
treatment for him.
실례합니다
모두 잘 들어주세요
Excuse me,
everybody listen up.
아무도 지금은 아파트를
떠나시면 안 됩니다
I'm gonna have to ask that nobody
leave the apartment at this time.
테라스 문에 이상하게
지문이 하나도 없어요
Terrace door's curiously
devoid of prints.
하나라도 찾아야 운이 좋은 건데
I'm lucky if I got one.
파티가 있는 날엔 항상
사람을 불러 청소하거든요
I always have the cleaners
come the day of a party.
헤크만 부인, 파티 중에
Mrs. Heckman, when did you notice
언제부터 헤크만 씨가
안 보이는 걸 아셨습니까
Mr. Heckman was
missing from the party?
몰랐어요. 그는 항상
몰래 다른 사람이랑 나가니까
I didn't. I mean, he's always
sneaking off with someone.
이런 만남은 남편이
일하는데 필요하기도 하고요
Social events are where
he made his deals.
파티에 온 사람 중에
Were there any people at the party
남편과 문제가 있었던
사람들이 있나요?
tonight that might have
a problem with your husband?
훤하죠 / 이름을 아세요?
Definitely. / You got a name?
펜만 주시겠어요?
You got a pen?
아쉽게도 모든 혈액 샘플은
피해자의 것이야
All the blood samples are
from the victim, unfortunately.
총에선 뭐 나온 거 없나?
Any luck with the guns?
그 포도주 가게에서 발사된 총이
맞다는 것은 확인했어요
Testing confirms they were the
weapons fired at the wine shop,
하지만 역시 지문은 없어요 / 고맙네
but no prints on either. / Thanks.
탄피 조사 결과는 ?
What about the casings?
브롱크스에서 일어난
미결 총기 사건 중에
Multiple case-to-case matches
with about a half a dozen
6건과 일치해요
unsolved Bronx shootings.
용의자는 '크레이지 에이시스'
라는 갱단의 멤버야
Main suspects, crazy
aces gang members.
- 그건 뭐예요?
- 라이터에 있던 지문 결과
- Whatcha got?
- Got a hit on your lighter print.
루이스 어코스타, 18살
소년원에 두 번 다녀왔고
Luis Accosta, 18,
two juvie stints,
폭행죄와 자동차 절도
크레이지 에이시스의 멤버
felony assault, grand theft
auto, member of crazy aces.
영상분석 담당자가 감시카메라
영상분석을 빨리 끝내야겠네요
The a/v techs should be
finish loading that surveillance video.
라이터를 떨어트리는 장면이
나오면 충분히 체포할 수 있어
If he lost that lighter on screen,
it's enough to make an arrest.
안경 때문에 한 놈도
얼굴을 제대로 볼 수가 없군
Can't get a positive facial read,
not even the one without glasses.
예, 카메라 위치 때문이에요
모자가 얼굴을 가려주네요
Yeah, it's the camera angle.
Hats are working against us.
저게 아마 어코스타일 거야
That's got to be Accosta.
문 쪽에 한 명 더 있어
Check the perp at the door.
행동을 보니 이 애는
별 짓은 안 한 거 같은데
Body language says that one's
in over his head.
겁에 질렸네요
Yeah, he's scared.
게다가 무장도 안 했고
And unarmed.
젠장, 어코스타가 라이터를
떨어뜨린 건 화면에 안 잡혔어요
Damn it.
Accosta lost the lighter off screen.
체포영장은 날아가 버렸군
There goes our arrest warrant.
헥터, 쏴버려
Hector, blast that fool.
이름이에요
고맙다, 바보들아
Got a name.
Thank you for being stupid.
헥터라는 걸 알았네요
We got a Hector.
헥터의 신고식이었어
This was Hector's gang initiion.
말 되네요. 돈만 챙기려 했다면
더 고급스런 가게로 갔을 텐데
That makes sense. You don't hit
an upscale place for all the cash.
돈도 챙겼으니 죽이는 거지
And murder once you've
gotten the money.
여기요. 이것 보세요
here, check this out.
DNA를 찾을 수 있겠어요
We may have DNA after all.
이 캔 가져오셨어요? / 아니
You bagged this can? / No.
자네가 찍은 현장사진에는 없던 걸
It wasn't in your crime scene photos.
어쩌면 헥터가 돌아와서
가져갔을 지도 몰라요
Maybe Hector came back
and retrieved it.
친구인 어코스타에게 물어보지
I'll ask his friend Accosta.
산화되지 않은 걸 보니
난간에 흠집은 최근 거야
No oxidation.
The rail break is recent.
새들이 말을 못하는 게 아쉬워요
Yeah, well, too bad birds can't talk,
4미터 떨어져서 울새의
둥지가 있는데 말이에요
'cause there's a robin's
nest, like, 12 feet away.
조감도처럼 말이지
Bird's-eye view.
- 그랬을 수도 있죠, 뭐
- 이제 뭐 할 거야?
- Had to say it, right?
- What're you gonna do?
섬유를 찾았어
I got a fiber.
피해자의 셔츠와 일치하는 거야
It's consistent with our victim's shirt.
피해자는 재킷을 입고 있었잖아요?
He was wearing a jacket, right?
그러니까 얼굴부터 떨어졌다는 거지
Means he fell face-first.
자, 볼까요
Here we go.
난간에 핏자국이 있어요
There's blood on the ledge.
덩치가 커서 한 번에 떨어지지
못하고 부딪힌 거야
Guy that big wouldn't fall
clear of the building.
만약 자살이라면, 난간을
피해서 뛰어내렸을 거예요
if it was suicide,
he would've jumped over the rail.
그럼 우리는 사고인지
살인인지 알아내야겠군
So we're looking at an
accident or a homicide.
여기가 그놈들 소굴이에요
This is the aces' turf.
버려진 빌딩들을 옮겨 다니죠
They move from one condemned
building to another.
어코스타, 이리 좀 오지
Accosta, come here.
너 . 일어나
And you, stand up.
예의가 없네, 아저씨
It's not polite to point, man.
이름이 뭐 지?
what's your name?
토마스 페레즈요
Tomas Perez.
오늘 밤 너희가 한 짓이 찍힌
비디오테이프를 갖고 있는데
Got your escapade
on videotape tonight.
우리가 아니에요
우린 계속 여기 있었어요
Not us. We were in here.
그건 소용없어요
It's cold out.
- 이러면 골치 아프죠
- 합법적인 수색이야
- Man, this is harassment, man.
- It's a legal search.
약도 있네. 니들 우리가
이런 것도 잡아넣는 거 알지
Pack of gum. Punks knew
we were coming for 'em.
깨끗합니다
Cleaned up.
라이터를 찾나, 루이스?
Looking for your lighter, Luis?
오늘 밤 떨어뜨렸지
You dropped it tonight.
난 라이터 잘 잃어버려요
Man, I lose lighters all the time.
헥터라는 새 친구는
어디 있지?
Where's your new friend, Hector?
그런 애 모르는데요
Don't know any Hectors.
발사 잔여물 검사를
할 거니까
I'm testing for gunshot residue.
다들 이리 와
Come here.
손 이리 내
Hold out your hands.
뭐하는 거예요? 이건 또
무슨 실험이에요?
What are you doing, man? Whwhat
kind of experiment is this, man?
암 걸리는 거 아니에요?
Could give me cancer.
너, 이리 와 / 얼른!
you, come here. / Move it!
아무것도 못 찾을 걸요
You got nothing on us.
그렇지
points.
넌 오늘 사람을 죽였어. 페레즈
You murdered a man tonight, Perez.
네가 죽였다는 걸 증명하는
증거가 먼지 한 점 만큼만 있어도
If there's one speck of dust
out there that proves it,
반드시 찾아낼 거고
I will find it,
네가 한 짓에 대한
대가를 치러야할 거야
and you will answer for what you did.
어쩐 일로 검사님이
여기까지 오셨습니까?
what brings a prosecutor
to a crime lab?
이놈들 꼭 체포해야 합니다
I need an arrest on this one.
살인사건 수사할 때
제 목표도 항상 그렇습니다
That's always my goal
with homicide.
하지만 이번 사건은 언론에서
엄청 떠들어대고 있소
But this is the stuff
the papers clobber us with.
무고한 시민이 갱들에게
총 맞아 죽었다면서
Innocent people gunned
down by gangbangers.
무고한 백인 시민이죠
Innocent white people.
반장 입장에서 말은 쉽죠
You know, it's real easy for you.
정치가 이곳 실험실까지
간섭하지는 않으니까
The politics doesn't
come in here to your lab.
그건 제가 어떻게 할 수
있는 게 아닙니다
Not if I can help it.
내가 어떻게 해주면 되겠소?
What do you need from me?
여유를 주세요
최선을 다하고 있습니다
Space.
We're doing everything we can.
더 빨리 하시오
Do it faster.
반장님, 셋 중 두 놈은
바로 눈앞에 있잖습니까
Mac, we had two of the
three right in front of us.
눈에 띄는 핏자국도 없고
발사 잔여물도 나오지 않잖아
No visible blood spatter.
Negative for GSR.
그놈들이 씻은 게 분명한데
They obviously washed up.
확실한 증거가 없어
There was no move to make.
그건 뭔가?
What do you have?
경찰 출동 기록이요
Police dispatch log.
비디오에서 본 음료수 캔이
아주 말썽이네요
That soda can we saw in the
video was bothering me.
서점 점원이 놈들이 도망치는 걸
본 게 10시 15분 이랬는데
The bookstore clerk said
he saw them running at 10:15.
처음으로 연락받고 간 경찰이
도착한 건 10시 17분이에요
The first responding officer
arrived at 10:17.
시간이 비는군
Timeline rules out retrieval.
무장 안 했던 갱, 헥터가
Uh, the unarmed banger, Hector
그 와인 가게에 음료수 캔을
놓고 갔거든
left a soda can behind
in the wine shop.
DNA 찾게요? / 그런데 현장에서
그 캔을 찾을 수가 없어
DNA? / We didn't find it
at the scene.
미라도 라임 맛 음료수인데
Mirado brand, lime flavor.
모랜이 처음 도착한 경찰이지?
Moran was the first responder.
모랜은 기억력이 아주 좋아요
That's guy's got a memory
like an elephant.
좋아. 그에게 물어봐
Good. Ask him about it.
whoa!
음료수 캔?
Soda can?
본 적이 없는 걸
Never saw one.
복잡한 현장이였잖아요
Well, it was a busy scene.
모든 걸 기록하시니까
메모한 걸 찾아봐 주실래요?
You write down everything.
Can you check your memo book?
- 확실히 기억한다고
- 부탁해요, 게빈
- I'd remember it.
- Humor me, Gavin.
내가 적어놓았다면
분명 기억할 거야
If I wrote it down,
I'd remember it.
피해자를 살리느라 바빠서
Look, you were trying
to save a guy's life.
깜빡했을 수도 있잖아요
Easy to forget something.
깜빡했다고?
테일러 반장이 그러던가?
Forget something?
What, is that Taylor talking?
아뇨. 제 생각입니다
심각하게 받아들이진 마시고
No, it's me.
Come on, don't make this a thing.
그래, 늘 이런 식이야
윗사람들이 잘못해 놓고서는
It's an old game.
Higher-ups screw up,
현장 경관들을 탓하지
blame the uniform.
자네까지 이렇게 나올 줄은
정말 몰랐네, 도니
I never thought
you'd partake, Donnie.
선배, 저한테 메모한 걸 주세요
Gavin, give me your memo book.
명령이라도 됩니까, 형사님?
What, that an order, detective?
꼭 그래야만 한다면요
If you need it to be.
파티의 흥을 깨버린
이유가 여기 있지
There's a joke here
about crashing a party,
- 나 같으면 안 그럴 텐데
- 그래요
but I won't go there. / Good.
사인은 두부 손상이야
Cause of death--
blow to the head.
떨어질 때 받은 충격일 거예요
Which he sustained in the fall.
2층 난간의 핏자국에서 일치하는
DNA를 찾았거든요
We matched his DNA to blood
we found on the second floor ledge.
오른손에서는 꽃향기가 나
Floral scent on the right hand.
분석해 볼게요
저항한 흔적은요?
I'll get that broken down.
Signs of struggle?
오른쪽 엉덩이에 작은 멍이
두 군데 있을 뿐이야
Just two small bruises
on his right glute.
위장 속 내용물은요?
Stomach contents?
파티에 늘 등장하는 거지
닭고기, 샐러드, 초콜릿
What'd you'd expect at the party--
chicken, arugula, chocolate.
혈중 알코올 농도는 0.011%
Alcohol content-- .011.
술까지 취했다면, 이 남자를
Even drunk, it wouldn't be easy
to send a guy this big
자신이 가기 싫어하는 곳으로
데려가는 건 쉽지 않았겠죠?
where he didn't want to go, you know?
위 속 내용물을 더 분석해 볼게
I'll break the stomach contents
down further,
독극물 검사도 하고
run a tox screen for poison.
고마워요. 박사님 / 뭘
Okay. Thanks, doctor. / All right.
에이든, 멜빈 손에서 났던
향기가 뭔지 알아냈어
Hey, Aiden, I got the scent broken
down on Melvin's hand.
잘됐네요 / '의심'이라는
여자 향수였어
Good. / It's a woman's
perfume called suspicion.
그런데 그 부인은
향수 쓰지 않았던데요
Yeah, but his wife
wasn't wearing any.
여자들은 목이랑 손목
가슴 쪽에도 뿌리거든요
Women wear it on their neck,
wrists, cleavage.
그럼 다른 여자와 어울렸군
Maybe he was playing around.
저기요, 팔 부분에 많은
흠집이 있어요
You know, there are a lot
of scratches on the arms,
안 떨어지려고 애쓴 거 같은데
but he definitely fought the fall.
어깨에 묻었던 건
뭔지 찾았어?
You I.D. the substance
on his shoulder?
연어 기름이에요
It's salmon oil.
파티에서 연어 요리가 나왔으니
Well, they served salmon at the party.
예, 그런데 그걸 자기 등에
떨어뜨리는 사람은 없잖아요
Yeah, but nobody spills
it on their own back.
그렇네 / 이 옷에서 지문을
찾기는 어렵겠어요
True. / It's hard to get
prints off of clothing,
그런데 이건 굉장히 단단하게
짜여진 합성섬유라서
but this is a very tight
synthetic weave.
손바닥 일부 지문은 찾았어요
Got a partial handprint.
위치가 껴안으려고 한 건 아니네
Positioning doesn't look like a hug.
찍힌 자국의 오른쪽이
변질되었어요
Imprint's smudged
on the right side.
힘을 준 게 분명해요
Definitely indicates force.
트위스터 게임이라도
하지 않은 이상
Well, unless they were playing twister,
누군가 멜빈하고 싸운 거야
someone got physical with Melvin.
손가락 부분의 융기는
선명하게 남아 있지 않고요
There was no ridge
detail on the fingers.
딱 손바닥 자국만 있어요
We just got some on the palm.
어떤 멋쟁이가 그랬는지
손바닥 조사하러 가야겠네
Well, good, let's go print
some beautiful people, then.
현장으로 다시 가봐요
Back to the crime scene.
감사합니다
Thank you.
증거와 일치하는 향을 찾는 겁니다
I'm trying to match a fragrance here.
일치하면요?
what'd I win?
얘기 좀 해야죠
A conversation.
당신 향수가 멜빈 헤크만에게
배어 있었습니다
Your perfume was on Melvin Heckman.
그런 식으로 배역을 따내느니
그냥 기다릴걸 그랬어요
I'd rather wait tables than
get on that casting couch.
무슨 일이 있었죠?
So how'd it get there?
전 '죽음의 평결'이란 영화에서
주연을 맡기로 되있었는데
I was supposed to be
the lead in lethal verdict,
뇌종양에 걸린 변호사가 휴대전화
회사를 고소하는 이야기거든요
about a lawyer with a brain tumor
prosecuting a cell phone company.
절 잘랐어요
He fired me.
너 정말 왜 이러는 거야
You're supposed to be dying.
너 살 찐 거 알아?
자긴 그 영화 출연 못하겠다
You gained weight.
Honey, you're off the picture!
의사는 무식욕증이래
But my doctor says I'm anorexic.
그냥 가서 얼굴이나 가꿔
Go stuff your face on your own time.
살 뺄게요! 정말이에요!
I'll lose it! I swear!
꼴 보긴 싫었지만 브로드웨이를
떠나 LA로 갈 수 있는 기회였어요
Melvin was awful, but he was my
ticket from off-off broadway to L.A.
대니, 맞는 손바닥 지문을 찾았어요
Danny, I got a hit on the palm print.
- 잘됐네
- 누가 죽인건지 알게 되면
- That's cool.
- If you found the killer,
저한테도 좀 알려주세요
고맙다고 꽃이라도 보내게요
let me know who,
so I can send flowers.
여기 계세요
Don't move.
당신이 멜빈을 밀었다는
증거가 있습니다
We got evidence
that says you pushed him.
멜빈을 밀어요?
아니요, 아뇨, 아닙니다
Pushed him?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
오히려 전 멜빈에게 사정했어요
발코니 근처는 가지도 않았고요
I was begging him.
And nowhere near the balcony.
왜요? / 전 작가 겸 감독인데
Why? / Well, I'm a writer-director,
버지니아에서 광부로 일하신
제 할아버지의 인생을 얘기한 영화를
and I just finished a film for him
that's based on my grandfather's life
멜빈의 지원으로 완성했어요
제겐 아주 의미 있는 영화예요
as a coal miner in Virginia.
It's a very personal project.
그런데 다음 작품을 파라마운트에
팔기로 한 것을 알고서는
When he found out that I sold
my next project to paramount,
- 꽤 화가 났더군요
- 당신은 관심 없다고 했잖아요
- he went nuts.
- But you passed on that project.
관심 없어
I don't care.
주말에 있을 카나리 칼의
기념일에 개봉하겠어
I'm opening canary carl
memorial day weekend
안 돼요. 영화사에서 가만있지
않을 거예요. 멜빈, 제발...
nono, it'll get killed by pixar.
Melvin, please...
그만 꺼져, 해크!
Get lost, Hack!
그게 마지막으로 얘기한 거예요
That was the last time I spoke to him.
증명할 수 있어요?
Any proof of that?
예, 제 에이전트요
Yes, actually-- my agent.
그 뒤로 도서관에 있던 그 친구랑
한 세 시간쯤 통화했거든요
I was on the cell with him in the
library for, like, the next three hours.
그래요
휴대전화 좀 주시겠어요
Oh, good.
I'm gonna need your cell.
물론이죠
Sure.
여기요 / 고맙습니다
There you go. / Thanks.
저기, 잠깐만요
Hey, wait a minute.
멜빈이 몇 시에 떨어졌죠?
What time did he fall?
9시 30분쯤인데, 왜요?
About 9:30. Why?
어쩜 개봉 날짜를
못 바꿨겠네요
Maybe he never moved
the release date.
스텔라
Stella.
모랜이랑 얘기해 봤어?
Talk to Moran?
예
Yeah.
어쩜 모랜이 메모하면서 약간
혼란이 있었을 수도 있어요
May have been a little confusion
with his memo book notations.
모랜은 뭐라고 해?
What'd he say about it?
좀 민감하네요
A little touchy.
그 사람, 자기 교육관이었지?
He was your training officer.
그런 게 어떤 사이인지
아세요 / 그럼 알지
You know how it is. / Oh, yeah.
얼마 전엔 내 교육관이었던
사람을 우연히 만났었는데
Ran into one of mine
about a month ago.
그 사람은 내가 경찰서장이 되도
날 아가씨라고 부를게 분명해
I swear, if I were chief of police,
he'd still call me toots.
맞아요
Exactly.
문서에 다른 두 종류의
Hey, uh, you have a machine,
잉크가 사용된 걸 알아낼 수
있는 그런 기계도 있죠?
indicates if two different kinds of
ink are used on a document?
응. 비디오 스펙트럼 분석기
The video spectral comparitor.
이거 기록에 남기지 않고
해 볼 수 있을까요?
Can we run this through,
off the books?
사건번호 붙이지 않고? / 예
Without a case number? / Yeah.
별 게 아니라면 그에게 문제가
될 만한 기록은 안 남기고 싶어요
If it's nothing, I don't want anything
on record that calls him into question.
그러자. 비파괴 검사니까...
It is a nondestructive process.
고마워요 / 뭘
Thanks. / Sure.
자기 말이 맞았어
Hey, you were right.
모랜은 두 가지 필기구를 썼어
Moran used two inks.
검정색인데 서로 다른 펜이지
Both black, two separate pens.
첫 번째 펜으로 모든 걸 기록했어
First pen, he used to
write all the information.
용의자에 대한 진술과 상황들...
Description of the perps and such.
그 뒤에 다른 펜으로 이 부분을
몽땅 다 뭉개버렸어
Then he took another and
scratched out this entire section.
확실하게 적혀있어
"헥터, 음료수 캔"
Completely oblererated
"Hector, soda can,"
"오른쪽 뺨에 흉터"
"scar right cheek."
모랜이 자기가 잘 못 들었다고
생각했을 수도 있죠
Maybe Moran thought
he heard wrong?
세 가지 진술을 모두?
On all three points?
일부러 피해자의 마지막 진술을
무시한 게 분명해
He purposely withheld
the vic's dying declaration.
- 모랜이 그 캔을 치운 거야
- 잠깐, 그건 아직 모르잖아요
- Moran took that soda can.
- Wait, we don't know that.
멀리 치우지는 못했을 거야
현장에 돌아가 봐야겠어
But he couldn't have gotten far.
I'm going back to the scene
스텔라, 잠깐만요
Stela, wait.
제가 갈게요 / 플랙...
I'll do it. / Flack...
전 4년간 그와 함께 다녔어요
I rode with him for four years.
모랜이 어떤 식으로
생각했을지 제가 알아요
I know how he thinks.
알았어
All right.
잘 배워두라고, 신참
Remember all the lessons, rookie.
자네 실력이 여전해서
기쁘군, 도니
I'm glad a few things stuck, Donnie.
이건 정말 말도 안 돼요
제가 모랜을 안다고요
This doesn't make sense.
I know this guy.
한 지역에 20년간 있었다면
이런저런 관계를 맺기도 하지
A cop on the same beat
for 20 years makes ties.
갱들이랑요?
그럴 리 없어요, 스텔라
With gang members?
No way, Stella.
게빈은 그럴 사람이 아니에요
Gavin Moran's not on the take.
바로 전에 자기는 게빈이 증거를
훼손할 리 없다 했지만 아니잖아
An hour ago, you'd have sworn
he'd never tamper with evidence.
서로 도와서 총도 찾고
피해자를 살리려고 했어요
Helped me find the guns,
he tried to save the victim...
- 그건 생각 안 하세요?
- 잠깐만, 스텔라
- it doesn't add up.
- Wait a minute, wait.
이게 우리가 찾는 증거가
맞다고 판명되기 전까지는
We're getting ahead of ourselves until
we confirm that this is the evidence
앞서 단정 짓지 말자고
we're looking for.
또 귀찮게 하러 왔어요
I'm back to torture you.
한 여자의 심한 고통이
다른 여자의 일거리가 되기도 하죠
One woman's torture
is another woman's challenge.
아주 급한 것 같네요
That look says it's a rush.
- 여기서 기다리죠
- 그러세요
I'd like to wait here. / Sure.
추운 날씨 덕분에 DNA 보존이
잘 되어 있었어요
The cold temperature kept
the DNA samples nicely.
캔에서 두 명의 흔적을 찾았는데
There are two donors on the can.
신원미상 남자의 타액과
A saliva contribution
from an unknown male,
게빈 모랜 경사의 상피조직이에요
and an epithelial contribution
from sergeant Gavin Moran.
- 그리고 또 말씀드릴 게...
- 이 결과 확실한 거죠?
- And there's more...
- you sure this part is right?
그럼요
Absolutely.
모랜이 그 갱들을 봐준 거예요
Moran's in the gang's pocket.
그가 돈 때문에 그런 짓을
한 거 같지는 않아
I don't think he did it
for the money.
DNA 제공자 둘이 유전학적으로
부자지간인 걸 알 수 있어
The DNA donors have genetic profiles
that indice they're father and son.
그럴 리 없어요
That can't be right.
게빈에겐 보스톤 대학에 다니는
쌍둥이 딸들뿐이에요
Gavin's got twin daughters
at Boston college.
한 구역에서 20년이야
Same beat, 20 years.
플랙
Flack,
그 헥터라는 갱이
the banger named Hector...
모랜의 아들이야
he's Moran's son.
계좌 조사해봐
뭘 찾아야 하는지 알지?
Run his financials.
You know what to look for.
모랜이 말할 때까지
기다리면 안 될까요?
Why don't we wait until you
hear what he has to say?
이번 건은 주목받는 살인사건이야
게다가 이미 모랜은 우리들의
Don, we have a hot homicide and
we already know where Moran
사건해결을 방해했어
falls in our efforts to solve it.
그 엄마를 찾아봐
Find the mother.
엉덩이의 멍이
신발에 찍힌 거라고?
Glute bruise came from a shoe?
펠드만 스파이크힐이 유행이에요
This season's feldman stilettos.
데이터베이스에서 찾았어? 잘됐네
Footprint database came through? Nice.
캐리 브래드쇼가 항상
구두에 돈을 쏟아 붓기 때문이죠
Yeah, 'cause carrie bradshaw's
always knocking off savings and loans.
선배, 이런 힐은
데이터베이스에 없다고요
They don't database women's shoes.
나도 좀 알자
Enlighten me then.
그러죠. 선배 가족 중에는
구두하는 분이 없을 테고 해서
Okay, well, you're not the only
one with craftsmen in the family
이스트 86번가에서 구두를 파는
제 사촌 매니에게 물어봤어요
because I called my cousin Manny
who's a cobbler on east 86th.
눈물방울 모양 굽이라고 하니까
베버리 펠드만에 가라고 하더군요
Told him about the tear-drop heel,
and he sent me over to beverly feldman.
정말 그렇네
You're right.
눈물방울처럼 보여
Looks like a teardrop.
멍 사이의 거리로 봤을 때
I measured the distance
between the two bruises.
우리가 찾는 여자는
발 크기가 7 이에요
The woman we're looking for
wears a size seven.
그럼 신데렐라를 찾으러 가볼까
Let's go find Cinderella then.
자네는 증거를 훼손했네
You tampered with evidence.
내가 맡은 사건 증거야
My evidence.
- 무슨 말씀이신지...
- 확실하게 처리를 못했더군
- I'm not sure what...
- you were sloppy.
자네 DNA가 캔에 남아있었어
Your DNA is on that can...
자네 아들 것과 함께
as is your son's.
그리고 피해자의 마지막
진짜 진술도 우리가 확보했네
And we have the original
statement from the vic.
조합 변호사 불러주시죠
Call my union lawyer.
아들에게 기회가 남아있을 때
찾을 수 있게 어디 있는지 말해주게
Tell me where your son is
while he still has a chance.
내가 이야기를 풀어볼까
Let me start the story for you.
젊은 경찰이 새로운 구역에서
일하는데, 가족은 집에 있고
Young guy, new on the street,
family at home.
어떤 멍청이한테서
여자를 구해주게 되고
Saved a girl in the projects
from some meathead.
그 여잔 자네를 마치
슈퍼맨처럼 생각했겠지
She looked at you
like you're superman.
그렇게 지내다가
아들이 생겼을 테고
You turn around,
you've got a son.
돌봐주려고 같은 구역에서 계속
근무하겠다고 신청했겠지
You request to stay on the same beat
as a way to check in. But...
하지만 돈 좀 보내주고
가끔 들르는 것만으로는
financial support and the
occasional visits aren't as strong
아들이 갱들과 가까워지지
못하게 할 수 없지
as the lure of the gangs--
especially to a dominican kid
떳떳이 밝힐 수 없는 백인 아빠를
둔 히스패닉 계 아이라면 더더욱...
with a white father with
something to prove.
순찰하다가 강도사건에 출동해서
On tour,
you respond to a robbery,
진술을 적다가 그게
자네 아들 헥터인 줄 안 거야
get a description,
realize it's Hector, your son.
자네가 경찰이란 걸 이용해서
Father trumps cop.
아들을 감싸준 거지
You cover for him.
기회를 봐서 말이야
You're looking at time.
만약 그 말씀이 맞다면
제가 할 일은 이제 없겠군요
If that's my story,
sounds like the least I can do.
만약 헥터가 총을 쏜 게
아니라면 도와줄 수가 있네
If he's not the shooter, I can help.
헥터를 꼭 찾아야 돼
I just need to find him.
변호사를 불러 주십시오
Call my union lawyer.
이젠 경찰이 찾아오는 게
아주 지겹네요
I'm tired of you
people in my house.
- 질문에나 답해 주시지요
- 당신 말이 맞아요
- Just answer the question.
- You're right.
있는 힘껏 엉덩이를 걷어찼죠
I kicked him in the ass
as hard as I could.
왜 그랬는지 물어봐도 될까요?
May we ask why?
목숨을 구하려고요
To save his life.
그의 식습관에 대해
얘기했잖아요
I told you about his eating.
식습관이요?
정상 체중보다 90kg 더나갔어요
Eating? / Melvin was
200 pounds overweight,
하루에도 다섯 번 이상
신경질을 부리고
he had five tantrums a day,
콜레스테롤 수치가
엄청나게 치솟았죠
sky-high cholesterol levels.
단 건 독약이나 마찬가지였어요
Sweets were like poison to him.
단 걸 못 먹게 감시하셨군요
And you were the candy police.
집이나 사무실에서
단 걸 못 먹게 했죠
Exactly. I forbade sweets
at home and at his office.
파티에 가면 웨이터에게 특별히
멜빈한테 사탕이 눈에 띄지 않게
And at parties, I gave specific
instructions to the waiters to keep
해달라고 부탁하곤 했어요
the candy trays away from him.
그래도 그이는 잔머리를 굴려서...
But he's wily...
멜빈!
Melvin!
딱 하나만!
It's just one!
정말 잠시도 눈을
뗄 수 없다니까
Can't trust you for a minute.
은이네요
Silver.
커프스 버튼을 하고 있었나요?
He wore cuff links?
그의 재킷 소매에
흔적이 있었습니다
His jacket sleeves had marks.
그 중 하나는 벽 때문에
생긴 흔적이겠군요
One of them was probably from the wall.
맞아요
You're right.
댁들은 내가 멜빈을 발코니에서
차버렸다고 생각하는 거예요?
What do you think?
I kicked him off the balcony?
그럴 수도 있단 생각이 듭니다만
It crossed our mind.
말했지만 난 멜빈을 사랑했어요
I told you... I loved that man.
실례할게요
Excuse me.
다시 시체 조사하러 가자
Back to the body.
수년간 블랑카 바스케즈에게
수표를 보내줬더군요
Years of checks made out
to a Blanca Vasquez.
주소는 브롱크스에 있는
카모디 가(街)로요
Bronx address, carmody street.
반장님 / 왜?
Mac. / What?
- 만약에 그 아들이...
- 플랙, 정신 똑바로 차리게
- If it was his son...
- Flack, I need your head on straight.
그래야죠 / 좋아
It is. / Good.
나하고 같이 체포하러 가세
You ready to go hunting with me.
일 끝나고 집에 오니까
헥터가 짐 싸서 나갔더군요
When I got home from work,
I saw that Hector packed.
그리고 메시지를 들었지요
And then I heard the message.
뭐라고 하던가요?
What did he say?
애틀랜타에 있는 친척에게
간다고 했어요
He said he's going to our
cousin's in Atlanta.
그리고 토마스 페레즈가 오면
대답하지 말란 말도요
Said not to answer the door
if Tomas Perez came by.
전화해봤는데
전화가 꺼져 있어요
I tried calling, but his cell is off.
바스케즈 부인, 댁의 자동응답기를
가지고 가야 되겠습니다만
Mrs. Vasquez, we need to take
your answering machine.
그러세요
Of course.
좋은 소식과 나쁜 소식
두 가지로군
Good news and bad news.
헥터가 신고식에 실패했고
Hector failed the initiation.
이제 갱들은 헥터를
죽이려고 하는군
Now they want him dead.
휴대전화에 다시 걸어봐
Call his cell phone again.
방금 다섯 번이나 했잖아요
계속 꺼져 있어요
Just did-- five times. Still off.
위치 추적될까봐 그런 건가
Probably knows it can be tracked.
엄마, 저 지금 버스정류장인데
걱정하지 마세요
Mama, I'm at the bus station.
Don't worry.
만약 토마스 페레즈가 오면
문 열어주지 마시고
If Tomas Perez comes by,
don't open the door.
전 애틀랜타에 갔다고 말해주세요
Tell him I went to Atlanta.
어쨌든, 애틀랜타에는
절대 안 갔단 뜻이네요
All right, that means
he's anywhere but Atlanta.
배경에 들리는 소리를
따로 추출해 볼게요
I'm going to isolate
that background noise.
십대들은 도망갈 때
보통 멀리 가지 않아
When teens run,
they usually don't go far.
들었어? / 예, 큰 스피커 소리
같은데요. 따로 뽑아볼게요
Hear that? / Yeah, some kind
of loudspeaker. Let me bring it up.
이 주파수를 분리해서...
들어보죠
I can isolate that frequency.
Here we go.
윗포드 9번가
Whitford-ninth street.
파크 슬로프의 윗포드 9번가
Whitford-ninth in park slope.
브룩클린이네요. 제가
바스케즈 부인에게 전화할게요
Brooklyn. I'm gonna
call Mrs. Vasquez.
헥터의 어머니가 여기서 일했었대
Hector's mother worked here.
아들이 어렸을 때 가끔씩
데리고 오곤 했대
Used to bring him with
her when he was little,
공장이 문 닫기 전에 말이야
before the plant closed.
이번 일은 제가
안 맡았으면 좋았을걸
I really wish I wasn't part of this.
반장님은 자기가 태도를
확실히 하길 바라시는 거야
Mac wants to make sure you are.
제가 동료를 잡아넣는 걸
보고 싶으신가 보죠
He obviously enjoys
watching me nail a friend.
아니. 그저 자기가 제대로
일하길 원하시는 거야
No, he's just looking out for you.
뭔가 있는데요
I got something.
헥터 바스케즈!
뉴욕경찰이다!
Hector Vasquez! NYPD!
저기 있네
There he is.
반장님, 헥터가 반장님 쪽으로
가고 있어요. 저희가 주위를 맡을게요
Hey, Mac, he's heading out toward you.
We're going to cover the perimeter.
얘야, 괜찮단다
Son, it's okay.
전 아무 짓도 안 했어요!
I didn't do anything!
우리가 그걸 증명할 수 있게
도와다오, 알겠니?
You're gonna help us
prove it, all right?
가자!
Come on!
피해자가 죽기 전, 히스패닉 계에
오른쪽 뺨에 흉터가 있고
We have a dying victim's statement
ID'ing a hispanic teen named Hector,
헥터라는 10대 소년이
있었다고 진술했단다
scar on the right cheek.
네가 음료수 마시는 장면이
찍힌 비디오도 있다
You're on tape drinking
from a soda can.
그 음료수 캔도 가지고 있지
We have that soda can.
네 DNA가 남아있었지
It contains your DNA.
네가 우릴 도와준다면
If you help us,
뭔가 해결할 방법이 있을 거야
there may be a way out of this.
전 경찰들 안 믿어요
I don't trust cops.
이건 네 아버지와는
아무 관련 없는 일이야
This has nothing
to do with your father.
- 그 사람보고 싶지 않아요
- 그럴 필요는 없다
- I don't want to see him.
- You don't have to.
단지 그것 때문에 네 인생을
망치지 않길 바란다
But don't throw your life away
just to get back at him.
너에게 기회를 주려는 거야
I'm offering you a chance.
제가 그 사람을 쏜 게 아니에요
I didn't shoot that man.
그럼 누가 쐈지?
Who did?
걔네들이 절 죽일 거예요
They'll kill me.
우리가 그 놈들을 잡지 못하면
정말 그럴 지도 모른다
They will if we don't lock them up.
씨 독... / 현금 몽땅 내놔!
C-dog... / give me your cash!
빨리!
Hurry up!
토마스 페레즈요
Tomas Perez.
어쩌다 그렇게 됐지?
How'd it go down?
걔네들이 그 가게 아저씨랑
한 판 해보라고 했어요
They said they wanted to front
this cracker at the store.
가게를 털려고 했던 건 몰랐어요
I didn't know they were robbing him.
그런데 씨 독이 총을 주면서...
Then C-dog gave me his gun...
헥터, 쏴버려!
Hector, blast him!
못 해! / 뭐라고?
No way. / What?
뭐 해, 나가자!
Come on, let's go!
얼른!
Come on!
걔네 말을 안 들었기 때문에
I let them down.
저에게 어떻게 할 지 알았어요
I knew what they'd do.
그래서 걔네들이 똑바로 갈 때
전 중간에 랭글리 가로 빠졌어요
So I cut down langley street
when they ran straight.
그 뒤로는 못 봤어요
I haven't seen 'em since.
최대한 빨리 체포해요
양배추 좀 더 넣어주시오
I want him booked ASAP.
More sauerkraut, okay?
헥터 바스케즈가 쏜 게 아닙니다
Hector Vasquez
wasn't the shooter.
그렇다고 잡은 놈을 놔줍니까
I don't release
a bird in the hand.
아, 그 정도면 됐소
Okay, that's good, right there.
그저 뉴스에 내보내려고
체포하려는 건가요
Meaning you have an arrest
for the 6:00 news.
그 놈이 가게에서 한 짓을 봐요
That kid went willingly into that store.
사람이 죽었소
그 녀석 체포해야 합니다
A man is dead.
I want him arrested.
E급 살인죄로요
Murder in e commission of a felony.
- 그럼 문제가 있습니다
- 뭔데요?
- Then we have a problem.
- What's that?
피해자의 진술과 음료수 캔
The vic's statement, the soda can...
둘 다 훼손되었거든요
they're both compromised.
모랜은 봐 줄 수도 있어요
정말입니다
Moran's next on my list, believe me.
우선 이 녀석부터 잡아넣어요
자백으로 충분하잖아요
But first I want this kid.
His confession is enough.
그랬다가 다음 주에 진범들이
또 사고 치면 뭐라고 하시게요?
So what happens next week,
when the aces strike again?
반장님, 점심 밥맛
떨어지게 하는군요
You're ruining my lunch.
헥터는 우선 놔두고
우두머리를 잡을 겁니다
Let Hector flip,
we'll cut off their head.
그럼 페레즈에 대한 증거가 있어야죠
We need evidence against Perez.
그렇지 않으면 배심원들은
세 녀석을 모두 같이 볼 겁니다
Otherwise a jury will see three
punks all pointing fingers.
- 알겠습니다
- 반장님에게 준 시간 말입니다
- I'll get it.
- Mac, that space I gave you?
얼마 안 남았어요
It's running out.
그의 혈액으로 독극물 검사를
해봤는데 독은 없었어
So I ran a tox screen on
his blood-- there's no poison.
위 속 내용물도 자세히
검사해 봤는데
I broke down the stomach
contents further.
음식물에도 독은 없어
No poison in anything he ingested.
내용물이 뭐라고 했죠?
What were the contents again?
닭고기, 샐러드, 초콜릿
Chchicken, arugula, chocolate.
부인이 그렇게 못 먹게 했는데도
몰래 트러플을 먹었나봐요
All that effort by Mrs. Heckman,
he still got a truffle past her.
트러플? / 네
(트러플 : 초콜릿 과자)
truffle? / Yeah.
아니, 그렇게 함유율이
높진 않은데
No. The carbate content
wasn't that high.
그냥 싼 밀크초콜릿이야
This is a cheaper milk chocolate.
부인이 말하길 집에서는 절대
단 걸 못 먹게 했다던데요
Mrs. Heckman said she
didn't allow sweets in the hsese.
다른 사람이 줬을 수도 있죠
Maybe someone gave it to him.
어디서 얻었든지
Got it somewhere.
초콜릿은 거의 소화되지 않았거든
Chocolate was barely digested.
아마도 떨어지기 바로 전에
초콜릿을 먹었을 거야
Swallowing it was probably
the last thing he did before he fell.
죽기 전 마지막으로 한 일이네
The last thing he did.
제가 새들이 말을 해주면
좋겠다고 얘기했던가요?
Dii I mention that I wish
birds could talk?
그랬던 거 같아
I think you did.
이것 좀 봐
Check it out.
초콜릿 포장지야
Candy wrappers.
울새들은 길거리 쓰레기통에라도
Robins make their nests
from whatever's available,
가능만 하다면 둥지를 짓는데요
even if it's trash on the street.
포장지가 많이 떨어져 있는걸
That's a lot of candy wrappers
for this kind of neighborhood.
맞아요. 이곳 주변에는
이런 거 파는 가게도 없는데
You're right. And there's not
a corner store for blocks.
멜빈은 여기 바람 쐬러
나왔던 게 아니야
Melvin didn't come out here
for fresh air.
가고일이 이빨이 있었던가요?
Do gargoyles have teeth?
조심해요
Be careful.
초콜릿이라니
Candy bars.
은닉품이로군
A stash.
도저히 하나만 먹을 수
없었던 거예요
He ate a piece,
but he couldn't have just one.
술기운 때문에 부주의해져서...
Alcohol makes him careless...
뉴욕에서 힘깨나 쓴단 사람이
부인에게 꼼짝 못해 죽어버렸네
the most feared man in New York
dies from fear of his own wife.
그 부인이 자기를 사랑했던
유일한 사람이었는데 말이에요
And she was the only one
that loved him.
총이 발사된 위치를 조사해서
헥터의 말이 진짜라는 걸 알아냈어요
We've confirmed that Hector was telling
the truth about where the shooter stood...
하지만 그걸로 누가 총을
쐈는지는 밝힐 수가 없어
but it doesn't prove who the shooter is.
사건이 모랜하고 연결돼 있어서
플랙에게 영향을 끼치고 있어요
This whole Moran thing has
really done a number on Flack.
플랙은 제대로 일해 왔어
이번 일도 잘 해낼 거야
He's been by the book,
he'll come out clean on this.
그런 뜻이 아니었는데
That's not what I mean.
뭣 좀 알아내셨어요?
Well, what do you got?
이 병들이 결국 우리를
도와주게 될 거 같아
Those bottles may have worked
in our favor after all.
오, 좋은데
Oh, nice.
이제 총도 가지고 다녀, 페레즈?
You carrying a gun now, Perez?
길에서 주은 거예요
I found that in the street.
갖다놓으러 가는 길이었어요
I was on my way to turn it in.
헥터 찾으려고 다닐 필요 없어
우리가 먼저 찾았거든
Don't bother looking for Hector.
We found him first.
아주 재밌는 얘길 해주더군
He told us an interesting story.
윗옷 벗어
Take off your jacket.
내 옷을요? / 영장도
갖고 왔단다, 이 자식아
My jacket? / We got a
warrant for it, maggot.
빨리 벗어
Take it off.
샘플들의 크로마토그램이
서로 일치해
The samples have
identical chromatograms.
그리고 발사 위치에
튄 자국들과도 일치해요
And the spatter's consistent
with the shooter's position.
페레즈는 이 옷은 가지고
있어도 된다고 생각한 거야
Perez thought it was safe
to keep his jacket
피가 안 묻었으니까
because he didn't get blood on it.
와인 한 병 때문에
잡힐 거라곤 생각 못했겠죠
Didn't expect to be brought down
by a bottle of white wine.
빠르게 튄 '샤르도네'이지
high velocity chardonnay spatter.
여피족이 이겼네요
Score one for the yuppies.
와인은 인공으로 만든 것 중에
Because of its vast array
of components,
성분 서열이 광범위한데
wine is one of the few
man-made subjects
그게 서로 일치했어
that can be exclusively matched.
검사가 페레즈와 어코스타를
잡으려고 바삐 움직이고 있네
McShane's moving quickly
on Perez and Accosta.
헥터에게는 거래를 제안했지
He offered Hector a deal.
다시 시작할 기회를 주는 거야
Gave him a chance to start over.
모랜은 어떻게 되죠?
What about Moran?
지금 연행하러 가는 중이야
I'm going to pick him up now.
반장님 / 증거를 훼손한 순간부터
그는 경찰 자격을 잃은 거야
Mac... / when he tampered with
evidence, he forfeited his badge.
그건 자신도 알고 있고
자네도 알아둬야 하네
He knew that.
You need to know that.
압니다
I do.
부탁 하나만 해도 될까요
And I have a request.
거물을 보내셨구먼
They sent the big guns.
좋아요. 이렇게 하기로 해요
All right, this is what's happening.
같이 중앙 등재소로 가는 겁니다
We're going to central booking.
가는 길에 변호사에게 전화하고
You'll call your lawyer on the way.
반장님이 검사한테 당신이
토마스 페레즈를 기소하는데
Detective Taylor spoke to McShane
who agrees that making too much hay
크게 일조했다고 얘기했고
검사도 동의했으니까
with you will hurt the prosecution
against Tomas Perez.
검사가 강제퇴직을 권할 거예요
연금은 받을 수 있어요
McShane's gonna recommend
forced retirement. Save your pension.
제가 안드레아한테 전화할까요?
Do you need me to call Andrea?
아니. 내가 오늘 밤 얘기하지
Nah. I'll sit her down tonight.
갈까요?
Ready?
여기서 연행하는 건가?
Gonna hook me up here?
우린 그냥 같이 담배나 피우러
가는 것처럼 나가면 되는 거예요
You and I are walking out of here
like we're going for a smoke.
번역 수정
손성봉(shon9795@nate.com)
맞춤법 교정
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀